Now commencing
the 57th Exterior Scouting Mission!
Move out!
We believe that the basement
of Eren Jaeger's home
in Shiganshina District
houses a secret of the Titans
that not even he is aware of.
We are to head there.
You rookies will be here,
between the cart guard team
and the scout support team.
Here, you will run alongside spare horses
and relay signals.
Our Special Operations Squad
will be positioned here,
on standby at the rear of the center rank.
This is the safest position
in the formation.
Not even the supply wagons
get this level of treatment.
This isn't an Abnormal.
- Cis!
- It has intelligence!
It's just like the Armored Titan,
the Colossal Titan, and Eren!
It's a human clad in a Titan body!
This one is way more athletic
than the other ones!
Damn! We were...
We were too naive!
She's protecting her nape?
Damn it! There's no escape now!
Jean!
Avenge that suicidal maniac!
She stopped?
It was her! She killed him!
That maniac finally got himself killed
as part of the right wing!
She killed him!
I'd say we bought enough time!
Now let's get away from her, quick!
What?
Oh, no.
Why?
Is she heading for Eren?
How is your omnidirectional
mobility gear, Armin?
It's all right.
It unclasped properly,
so it doesn't seem to be broken.
I see. That's good to hear.
But now what? We only have one horse.
If Jean's horse comes back, all three
of us can get moving again, but...
Damn it! What's the deal?
Reiner's horse came back. Why won't mine?
And we can't afford
to stay here any longer.
Worst case scenario,
we'll have to leave someone here.
How will we choose
who that someone should be?
Armin, because he's hurt?
Reiner, because he's big
and would be hard to ride with?
Or should I go look for my horse on foot?
Damn it!
It's screwed up
that we even have to consider that!
The three of us just managed
to escape death!
This is one hell of a raw deal!
Armin.
Hey, Armin!
I take it you're still a bit mixed-up?
Yes.
I'm still a little dazed.
I see.
Still, we need to decide now.
It's a difficult choice,
but it looks like one of us
has to stay behind.
Wait!
Let's fire a smoke signal first.
If the formation kept moving forward,
Row 4, Squad 3 should be nearby now.
That was an emergency smoke signal.
I doubt it's enough
to get our point across though.
Armin, we'll only wait for three minutes.
By then,
- we need to choose who'll stay--
- I'll stay.
But in exchange,
I need you to report something.
Only to Commander Erwin, if possible.
No, wait. Armin.
You can report it yourself.
Someone is coming!
And they've brought two horses!
That's...
Christa!
Guys! Are you okay?
What?
Hey, that's my horse!
Whoa, there. Calm down, Buchwald!
He came racing my way.
Something must have really spooked him.
Did you guys fight a Titan?
Armin!
You're hurt!
Are you all right?
Yes, more or less.
I'm impressed you willingly came here
after seeing that smoke signal.
I happened to be nearby.
Plus, I had found Jean's horse.
You have a way with horses.
Not to mention,
a remarkable sense of virtue.
We owe you one.
I'm just glad.
I'm very glad that
the worst didn't happen to you guys.
She's a goddess.
A goddess.
I want to marry her.
Well, we better hurry back into formation!
Oh, yes!
There should be orders to retreat soon!
Still, turning back not even an hour
after leaving the wall?
Things look way grimmer than I thought.
Plus, she's headed away from
the lead command squad for some reason.
She?
Green smoke signals?
It sounds like the plan is to change
the route and continue the operation.
Oh, no!
They are not ordering us to retreat?
What the hell is Commander Erwin thinking?
All soldiers have the authority to decide
if the operation can't continue.
Have the signals not reached
the command squad?
Whether or not they know,
we only have one option in this situation.
Defer to their judgment.
Smoke signals. Green.
Oruo. You fire it.
Understood, sir!
It feels like we're making
smooth progress right now.
But I wonder how things actually are.
I wonder if people have already died
on the front line.
Reporting, sir!
It's an oral message!
Right wing Scouts, decimated!
Detection network, partially out!
Please pass this message on to the left!
You heard him, Petra.
Go.
Yes, sir!
The right wing?
Isn't that where Armin is?
Still, he and the others
are positioned closer to the center.
The Titans couldn't have advanced
that far in.
Black signals?
An Abnormal?
Eren. You fire it.
Yes, sir!
This is disgraceful.
We've let them get pretty deep
inside the formation.
Just over there is a Titan.
Below that black smoke,
someone is fighting?
Damn!
Look down here, you monster!
Now!
Three spots at once!
She seems pretty smart,
but she can't defend against all of them!
Cut her spine, ligaments,
or anywhere else that can stop her!
Attack!
So many are dead because of you!
We're going to torture you to death!
She jumped?
Let go!
Reporting takes priority!
I have to let them know about that one!
An Abnormal?
This far in?
Let's take it out!
We can't let it get any further in!
The right wing has been wiped out?
Then why aren't we retreating?
I don't know!
Commander's orders!
Just pass the message on to the left!
What's the deal?
We've been going east for a while now.
FIRST ROW, THIRTEENTH
SCOUT
Yes, and our destination
is the old city to the south.
At this rate, the formation
is going to run right into it!
Yes.
There it is.
A forest of giant trees!
It looks like Titans
have passed through here.
The path is devoid of vegetation.
Even the wagons could get through here.
Inform those behind us
that only the center cart guard team
is to enter the forest.
- Yes, sir!
Excuse me, sir.
It looks like the center rank
is entering the forest.
We'll bump into the forest
if we keep going.
Then we go around.
Yes, sir!
Hey, now.
What are we doing
at this tourist attraction?
Now we're really straying
from our original destination
and return point!
I don't know.
I don't know,
but this is what Commander Erwin decided.
He seems to have some kind of plan
in mind, but...
Plan? Are you kidding me?
What? Is he going to throw a welcome party
for us rookies at this tourist spot?
No, I don't think so.
That was a joke.
Either way,
we got that giant broad after us.
Regardless of what plan he has,
we can't afford to stop here.
My guess is we're passing through here
on our way to somewhere else.
All soldiers, halt!
All right! Listen up, rookies!
We're now going to
take up intercept positions!
Unsheathe and wait in the trees!
If any Titans try to enter the forest,
stop them with full force!
What?
Sir?
- Why would we need to--
- Shut up and follow orders!
You've got to be kidding me.
What the hell is happening?
Hey.
It looks like only the center rank went
into the forest.
What does that mean for the formation?
There is no formation anymore.
The forest is blocking us, side squads,
so our only choice is to go around.
We've lost our spotting capabilities.
Why didn't we change course
and avoid the forest altogether?
Did Commander Erwin misread his map
or something?
I don't know.
It's possible we got pushed here,
trying to avoid the threat
on the right side.
Maybe.
This is insane.
First, we abandon our original plan
of establishing a logistics base.
Then instead of running home with
our tails between our legs like we should,
we go on a daring sightseeing tour.
And if that wasn't enough,
now we're just supposed to stand here
and keep Titans out of the forest?
Him and his idiotic orders.
He's going to hear you.
And he doesn't even explain anything.
That's a new one to me.
But I doubt he's that calm
on the inside either.
What do you mean?
Sometimes leaders get deemed incompetent
by their men in extreme situations
and end up dying
from mysterious stab wounds to the back.
It's not that rare. That's all I'm saying.
Jean, what are you thinking of doing?
Relax, will you?
I'm just a little irritated
at this whole situation.
I'm going to follow orders, of course.
Keeping Titans out of the forest?
You agree that's
what we should do too, right?
You look like you know something.
Well...
A 5-meter Titan is approaching!
Why did he bring the platoon here?
Just what is Commander Erwin thinking?
No, that's not right.
That isn't what I should be asking.
What I should be asking is,
what if the Female Titan is pursuing Eren
and the Commander is aware of that?
Captain!
Captain Levi!
What?
"What?"
This is a forest, sir!
We have no way of detecting
the approaching Titans this far in
with only the center rank!
Something seems to be on our right too.
How are we supposed to avoid the Titans
or protect the wagons now?
Quit whining about the obvious.
We can't do any of those things anymore.
But why?
Take a good look around, Eren.
See all these absurdly huge trees?
This is the perfect environment
for using omnidirectional mobility gear.
And use that middling head of yours
to think.
Use your brain for once
if you don't want to die.
Yes, sir!
I see.
I'm still new to this, that's why
I don't understand the situation.
And he won't give me a straight answer
because I still need to learn for myself.
I bet that's how these experts learned
to fight too.
Damn it. What are we doing here?
Seriously.
What the hell is going on?
What?
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me no one knows
what's going on?
Not even Captain Levi?
If my theory is correct
that the Female Titan is after Eren,
then there's only one reason
why we've come here.
Commander Erwin intends
to confront her here!
Armin.
Our order is to keep Titans
out of the forest, right?
In other words,
we don't need to actually fight them.
Right?
- A black smoke signal?
- From right behind us!
It must be whatever is on the right!
Draw your swords.
If it shows itself,
we'll only have a moment.
Move!
It's fast!
There's no way to avoid it
inside this forest!
It's catching up!
Captain! Let's switch
to omnidirectional mobility!
Captain!
You're not going anywhere!
Reinforcements from the rear!
Captain! Give your orders!
Let's take it out! It's dangerous!
We should take care of it!
I'll cut it to shreds!
Idiot! You walked
right into your own doom!
What you're chasing
is a team of expert Titan-killers!
Captain Levi!
Captain!
- Please give us orders!
- It's about to catch up to us!
Let's take it out here!
That's why we entered this forest!
Isn't it, Captain?
Captain! Your orders!
Everyone, cover your ears.
The Female Titan continues to chase them,
leaving a bloodbath behind.
Eren can only flee as he watches
his comrades die before his very eyes.
Amid this, he's forced to make a decision.